Hello!
I'm Sifu Mallon with the Clearwater Kung Fu Center.
This is my assistant Melissa.
And this is women's self defense tactics.
This one that we're working right now, is called our double outside block.
To practice one, you stand with your feet, shoulder width apart.
You're going to bring your right hand blocking, outside block.
Your left hand comes behind it or actually in front of it, palm block.
You're going to side step to the side, with your left foot.
And then, you're going to push to your right.
Again, so goes one, two, three.
The side step is to get your body off center.
So that means, if I'm stepping right here, I step here and my body still stays here.
That means that the attacker can still hit me.
So I want a side step and move my body.
The block, one, two, side step, move the body.
O.k.
So Melissa, you're facing me, right?
And I'm the attacker.
So I'm going to throw, I'm going to throw my right hand.
Melissa's going to come up with her right hand going outside block, one.
O.k.
Now out here and now left hand here.
So these two movements are simultaneous.
Now she's going to step forward, her left foot.
And lunge and push me off to the side.
That's it.
The idea with this block is to use your opponent's energy.
Meaning that, as I'm coming this way, right.
And you're doing one and two, three and push.
You're using my energy to push me past you.
Again, that's it.
This is double outside block, women's self defense.